How much do you spend on looking after yourself each month?
你每月会花多少钱打理自己？
We all like to look and feel good, so it's nice to spend money on ourselves sometimes!
我们都想外表光鲜、状态舒适，所以偶尔为自己花钱是件很美好的事！
You might spend your hard-earned cash on visiting the hairdresser, a gym membership or pampering yourself with a massage.
你可能会把辛苦赚来的钱花在去理发店、办健身会员，或是享受按摩放松上。
When it comes to hair and beauty, the average UK household spends just under 2% of their budget, according to personal finance experts, Nimble Fins.
个人理财专家Nimble Fins的数据显示，在美发美容方面，英国家庭平均花费占预算的近2%。
That's about £38 a month if you have an annual salary of £30,000.
如果年薪3万英镑，每月大约花费38英镑。
Areas that were looked at in their survey included toiletries, cosmetics, and related electrical appliances, like hairdryers.
他们的调查涵盖了洗护用品、化妆品以及吹风机等相关电器。
However, it seems that some people spend much more than that.
然而，有些人的花费远高于这个数字。
The booking app for all things aesthetic, Pamperbook, carried out a survey in 2022 of 900 UK salons and freelancers. The results found that female clients who use the app spend, on average, £1,000 per month.
美容预约应用Pamperbook在2022年对英国900家美容院和自由从业者展开调查，结果显示，使用该应用的女性客户月均消费1000英镑。
The survey showed that the most popular treatments were lashes and lip fillers, while customers frequently visited hair salons for a blow dry.
调查显示，最受欢迎的项目是美睫和丰唇填充，顾客也常去理发店做吹风造型。
But it's not only women who spend money on beauty.
并非只有女性会在美容上花钱。
Though men and women visit spas more or less equally, according to the International Spa Association, or ISPA, men spend more on treatments.
国际水疗协会（ISPA）的数据显示，尽管男性与女性光顾水疗中心的频次大致相当，但男性在护理项目上的花费更高。
A national survey in 2019 found that male participants spend more on massages and facials per year than women – £501 to £445.
2019年的一项全国调查发现，男性受访者每年在按摩和面部护理上的花费高于女性——分别为501英镑和445英镑。
Garrett Mersberger, head of the ISPA, said: "Men are more aware that it's not just a thing I go to to get pampered. It's an actual lifestyle choice with benefits to my body, my wellness."
国际水疗协会负责人加勒特·梅斯伯格表示：“男性越发意识到，这不仅仅是去享受放松，实际上更是一种对身心有益的生活方式的选择。”
Whether you tend to spend money on these things or not, it can certainly feel good to treat yourself every now and then!
无论你是否习惯在这些方面花钱，偶尔犒劳自己的感觉真的很棒！